Now, here's just some quick guidelines for resisting self disclosure.
Now, we talked a lot about how you should self disclose, how it's a good thing.
Maybe you don't want to, maybe it's not the right person, maybe it's not the right situation.
So, if someone is trying to get you to disclose information, and you do not want to, don't allow yourself to be pushed, don't let people push you into disclosing something that you do not want to disclose, simply refuse.
Refuse to disclose, be assertive, but you can still be nice.
You don't have to be aggressive and mean, but, no I rather not talk about that.
No I can't talk about that.
No I'm not going to give you that information.
Be as direct as you can, about, "I'm not going to give you the information that you want", and then try to switch topics, and this you might see a little bit more in a work environment.
Well what did the boss say?
Well I can't tell you", "No but really like, What did the boss say?" Be firm, be direct, I can't give you that information, and then move on.
Don't put a stop to it.